In HDFC Ego Optima Sikar, the insurance company will not pay
even a single rupee claim for these treatments.
If you have
bought this plan or are thinking of buying it,
then you must
watch the video because the
benefits and coverage of this plan will
not be missed, you will get them
in the policy words and even from there it is
not so easy to read and understand them, so I,
Harvinder Singh, will
tell you each and every point of exclusion in today's video, that too
in very simple language, so stay tuned till the end of the video. Let's
start the video,
first waiting period. Waiting period means
how much time you will have to wait for any treatment. There are three major
categories in this, the first category is pre-existing
disease, that is, the
diseases that you are facing from the first day of buying the policy will be called
your pre-existing disease
and any treatment related to it will be done
only after 36 months of buying the policy. There are
one or two conditions for this. The first
condition is that when you buy the policy,
you will have to inform the insurance company about these major diseases on time.  You
must mention this, otherwise, the
treatment related to it will not be covered even after 36 months. Secondly,
if you have ported from some other company to this plan, that is,
you had a
health insurance policy of some other company, now you have
changed it and taken Optima Seeker plan, then the
period of the previous policy, one year or
two years, whatever you have kept that policy, will
also be counted in this 36 months and
after that, your pre-existing disease will also be counted.
Now, the second category is friends,
specific illness, these are some special types of
diseases which are
listed on your screen right now, you will see this in your policy document, it will be counted
after 24 months from the time you
buy the policy. In
this also, the same thing is that if you have
ported the policy from some other company to this plan, then the
time of the previous policy will also be counted in it
and if there is any such disease which has
come under the category of your post, that is, Priya Singh's disease and also
comes under the category of specific illness, then the
ISP which has a longer waiting period is applicable.
Generally, the disease that has come in this category is
any kind of lump stone, kidney
stone, gall bladder stone, appendix, hernia,
files, all these are counted in specific diseases,
so the treatment related to it will be done
only after 24 months and the
final waiting period is friends, that is, the
standard exclusion is of 30 days, that is, from the time of
buying the policy till 30 days, you will not get any coverage for any
fever infection like dengue, malaria,
chikungunya,
you can get its related treatment done only after 30 days, the next category
is friends, investigation and evaluation, that is,
you get a
test done to check whether there is any problem
or not and nothing is found in it, then the
insurance company will never pay for such tests,
yes, if after getting the test done,
any problem is found, if there is
any medical problem, then you get admitted for it and get
treatment, then you will get the cost of these tests also,
but there is a test
which is not related to your treatment, whose
treatment  If the test you have taken is not related to it, then
its cost will also
not be covered in this. The next exclusion is friends, friends,
rest and rehabilitation and respite care.
After the doctor has completed the entire treatment, he tells the patient
that you only need bed rest so that
you can recover. During bed rest,
you may have to hire a
professional nurse or trained attendance for many tasks, which include
bathing,
feeding, dressing,
changing clothes, etc. So,
this policy will not cover the cost of such trained nurses and attendance. Sometimes it happens
that after a major treatment or a
major injury, the patient goes into
depression. So, there is
no coverage for any kind of social, psychological or emotional treatment or therapy.
Obesity and weight control, i.e., obesity
surgery, is also called a variety of surgery.
This is not a tax, but if
a patient wants to get this surgery done,
then it can be done.  The conditions have to be fully filed in this.
Firstly, there should be a doctor's
advice that this
obesity surgery is necessary for survival. Second,
this surgery should be done within the complete clinical protocol, that is, the
procedure should be
absolutely accurate according to the medical conditions.
Thirdly, the patient should be
above 18 years of age.
Fourthly, regarding the body mass index, the
patient's BMI index should be 40 or
more. The
operation can be done even at the index of 35. If the
patient has any disease due to which their
weight is not decreasing, such as any
heart disease, sleep apnea or type 2
diabetes, due to which their weight is not decreasing, then
variety surgery can be done even at the age of 35.
Change of gender
treatment means any treatment
related to your opposite sex. If you
want to get any characteristic treatment done, then this policy will not allow
cosmetic or plastic surgery. If
you want to get any plastic surgery done to beautify your face or any body part, then  If you
want to undergo surgery, this plan will
not support the surgery or bear the
expenses of the surgery. Yes,
after an accident, if the doctor says that
plastic surgery is necessary, or if someone gets burned or gets
burns, then
plastic surgery has to be done, which is a
medical necessity. Or if during cancer or any
other treatment, you have to undergo plastic
surgery, which is a medical
necessity, then plastic surgery will be done in that case, but you will
not get the money for the notification.
Hazards and Adventure India: These are such
sports and activities which involve a lot of
risk, such as
paragliding, bungee jumping, motor
racing, deep sea driving. You might have
heard a few days ago that it came in the news
that a submarine also went to the sea to see the Titanic's structure, in
which the
owner of the submarine company himself was aboard, and due to
some technical fault, that submarine
imploded inside, that is, it got crushed, and the
owner of the company also died in it, everyone else
also died in it, so such
activities which involve a lot of
risk are related to this.
If any treatment is required,
any injury is sustained, then
this plan will never cover it. Bridge
of Flaw means that the insured person is
involved in any such activity which is illegal. Suppose, the injured person is
running away from a bank or is taking away an ATM machine after uprooting
it and then the car meets with an accident, then the
insurance company will not cover the injury sustained during this time
because his basic activity is
illegal, so covering his medical injuries is
not justified. Excluded
Providers: This point is very important,
you should listen very carefully. These are the
hospitals and doctors which the company has
blacklisted. What is the reason, that is,
any of their processes is not correct, like the
claim process, billing process,
treatment process, the
company feels some doubts in it, hence the
company has put these doctors and hospitals
in the excluded list and
you will find this list on the company's website,
so you have to try this whenever  If you
take treatment,
your hospital should not be in the excluded list. If you
take treatment here, then no claim
company will entertain. Yes, there is a
clause of accident in this that if
after an accident,
a patient is taken to a hospital in the excluded list in an emergency, then the
initial treatment i.e.
first aid will be given to them, but
till their condition stabilizes, only that
treatment will be provided by the insurance company. The
claim for the entire treatment will not be made in the hospital.
Treatment of
alcoholism and other drug abuse, any
drug-related treatment,
any damage to the body due to excessive use of drugs,
withdrawal symptoms after quitting drugs,
or any such treatment which is
related to drugs, this company will never provide treatment.
Treatment in nature care clinics and
resorts, these are such facilities,
like in our India, if you
go to South India, in Kerala, you will find many such
resorts, which are five star resorts,
where you not only have the facility to stay, but
you can also have many nature resorts
and Ayurvedic facilities here.  You
can also get treatments done and they have
medicinal benefits, your body
becomes fresh and your immunity becomes
strong, but such
treatments that you give to your body
because they are not medically necessary, they will also
not be taxed in this plan. Diet
supplements like vitamins and minerals will not be taxed,
they will be taxed only in two conditions, the
first condition is that
if a doctor has prescribed them to you,
then this plan will tax them and secondly, if you had undergone
any treatment and
during recovery, the
doctor told you that you will have to take these multivitamins
and minerals, then also the
company will tax them, if you
buy them directly and take them, then
they will not be taxed in this plan, for refractive
error i.e. weak eyesight, near vision is
not visible well or far vision has become weak, then for that
if you want to get laser surgery done, then
this plan will do that
surgery, this plan will do that surgery,
but there is a condition for that, the
unit of your vision weakness should be
more than 7.5, if it is less than that then it will
definitely not be considered medical.  And that will
not be done if your vision impairment is more than 7:30
units, then this surgery can be done. These are
unproven treatments.
Many claims are rejected here
because of this reason. I have stomach
pain, I go
to the doctor, the doctor quickly applies glucose,
gives me pain reliever, and
starts my antibiotic. By the time
my reports come back, the
bill for Rs. 3540000 is generated. Now, if we
look at my reports, there is no problem, there is no
infection, no stone, no
lump, there is
no problem of any kind. So,
what will the doctor write in his report? The doctor will
write in his report that you were admitted with mild pain
and we gave you this treatment, whereas there is
no justification for
this treatment in your reports. So, this claim is
unproven treatment, that is, your
reports and tests do not justify your treatment. So, such
claims will also not be done. The
list that was there till now was not there.  Friends, these were the general
exclusions which will not be covered under this policy.
Now I am going to tell you about the specific exclusions of this policy,
which the company
itself has mentioned one by one, namely, treatment, which
we will not cover. The first name in this is
war, that is, if a war breaks out in the country, in which a
foreign enemy
attacks us, whether it is a nuclear war or a
biological war, then any
treatment related to that will not be covered under this plan. The
second is self-injury, if the
insured person injures
himself,
tries to commit suicide, that too will
not be covered under this policy. The next point is aggregate deductive, that is,
if you choose the deductive option, in
which you have to pay the
treatment money up to a limit, from your
pocket. The
insurance company gives you coverage after that only. So,
you will have to pay for the treatment up to the aggregate deductible limit yourself. The
insurance company will not pay for it if
you participate in any Army, Navy or Air Force
exercise.  If there is an
injury, this plan will
not cover it. If there is any congenital problem, any
disease or any defect in the body, that
too will not be covered under this plan. The
next point is friends, vaccination. The vaccination
of a child
starts from one month and after that, the
vaccination of the child is done till the age of 15 years. So, no
kind of vaccination
is taxed in this, except for one animal, that is,
if it is a monkey or
cat, then the vaccination done after that will be
taxed in this plan. Apart from that, no
other vaccination is taxed. Now the next
point is friends, OPD i.e. Outpatient
Department, you directly went to the doctor, the
doctor diagnosed fever,
gave you medicines for 3 days and you got well,
then this type of treatment in which
you did not have to be admitted and you did not have any
major problem, the
treatment of outpatient department will
also not be taxed. Non-medical
expenses i.e. consumables are those expenses
which are not of medical nature, such as
baby food, attendance charge, laundry charge,
these expenses are not taxed in medical treatment.
But
these expenses are incurred during the patient's stay in the hospital.
You will find these total expenses
in the list of Annexure B. I am
giving you the link of this list in the description.
You will not get the claim for all the items listed in it under this head. The
next category is friends, if you get any
contact lenses fitted, get glasses made
or if
you want to buy a hearing aid, that too will not be taxed in this plan. The
next point is that any
surgery or such expense which is related to your growth
i.e. related to baldness like
hair transplant, buying Vicks or
getting hair implants, then
any such surgery treatment or any other expense will
not be taxed in this. There is any
artificial body part like artificial hands, artificial
sticks for walking with support
or wheelchair. There is an oxygen concentrator.
Those who have COPD or not, that is, if they have
difficulty in breathing,
if they take an oxygen concentrator machine, then
coverage for such expenses will also not be available in this plan
and finally no  Even if a treatment that is
not necessarily medical is taken and a
claim is filed for it, the
company will not pass that claim. Friends,
while shooting the exclusions of Optima Seeker,
I missed two points. I am
shooting them again. The first point is that any treatment
related to maternity, that is, childbirth, will
not be waived.
Whether there are any complications or any
delivery, miscarriage charges will also
not be waived. But there are only two cases
where miscarriage charges can be waived.
First, if a
miscarriage occurs due to an accident, then this policy will waive that charge.
Second, if it is a medical termination of
pregnancy, that is, a pregnancy is terminated due to any medical reason, then this
policy will waive that charge as well. The next
exclusion is friends, sterilization and
fertility related treatment, that is, if you want to get
any treatment related to family planning,
such as sterilization, then this policy will
not waive it. If you have already undergone
sterilization and want to reverse it, then
that too will be waived
in the treatment display.  If you cannot conceive a baby normally, then you resort to
assisted reproduction. If
pregnancy is achieved with the help of a doctor, then
this policy will not cover treatments like IVF for that. These will also
remain in the exclusions of this plan. So
friends, I have told you all those points
of exclusion which are
written in your policy wordings, that is, now you do
not need to read the policy wordings at all for these exclusions. These are each and every
point which the company will not cover, for which
you will not get the money for treatment.
I have not missed a single point in this and
I have explained it to you in simple language. If you
still have any question related to these points
or there is any different treatment or coverage
that comes to your mind and you
want to ask, then immediately
comment in the comment section of this video. I will be
very happy to answer it. If
friends, through this video you feel that I have
created some value for you, that
some of your knowledge has increased, or that it will be easy for you to buy a plan
or use it,
then immediately like the video and subscribe
to the channel.  Please subscribe Bhole, I am Harvinder
Singh, I will meet you in the next video, till then take care of
yourself, stay happy and
healthy, Jai Hind
[Music]